<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on sigve nakken</title>
    <link>/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on sigve nakken</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I am a research scientist working in &lt;a href=&#34;http://radium.no/hovig&#34;&gt;Eivind Hovig’s group&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://radium.no&#34;&gt;Institute for Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt; in Oslo, Norway. Most of my activities involve cancer data science, i.e. analysis of data from high-throughput molecular profiling of tumor samples. During the last years, I have been part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cancergenomics.no&#34;&gt;Norwegian Cancer Genomics Consortium&lt;/a&gt;, a national effort on clinical cancer genomics. I am formally trained in computer sience from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ntnu.no&#34;&gt;NTNU&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umn.edu&#34;&gt;University of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;, and received my &lt;a href=&#34;/thesis/PhD_Thesis_SigveNakken.pdf&#34;&gt;PhD in computational biology&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmbn.no&#34;&gt;Centre for Molecular Biology and Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uio.no&#34;&gt;University of Oslo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing research activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cancer genome interpretation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of computational tools, prediction models, and resources that can translate cancer genomes into clinical decision support. I have initiated a project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sigven/pcgr&#34;&gt;Personal Cancer Genome Reporter (PCGR)&lt;/a&gt;, which is a platform-independent software workflow that generates a genomics-based knowledge report intended for precision oncology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computational modeling of drug response in cancer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessment of how systems biology knowledge and read-outs from omics technologies can be used in the prediction of &lt;em&gt;invitro&lt;/em&gt;/clinical drug response. Transformation of this knowledge into software and tools that serve to prioritize treatment strategies. Based on our participation in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.synapse.org/#!Synapse:syn4231880/wiki/235645&#34;&gt;DREAM challenge on Drug Combination Prediction&lt;/a&gt;, we have a collaboration with statisticians at &lt;a href=&#34;http://biginsight.no&#34;&gt;BigInsight, University of Oslo&lt;/a&gt; on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cancer predisposition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application of high-throughput seqencing to idenify variants associated with risk of cancer development. Enabling personalized (gene, gender, age) estimations of cancer risk in Lynch Syndrome patients (see website for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lscarisk.org&#34;&gt;Prospective Lynch Syndrome Database&lt;/a&gt;). Collaborative work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ous-research.no/moller/&#34;&gt;Dr. Pål Møller&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ous-research.no/home/hovig/Staff/17008&#34;&gt;Dr. Mev Dominguez-Valentin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mutational patterns in the human genome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a long-standing interest in the application of computational approaches to identify patterns in the distribution of genomic aberrations (both along the linear and three-dimensional genome), and specifically characterization and understanding of differences and similarities between the germline and the soma. Collaborative work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ous-research.no/hovig/&#34;&gt;Dr. Pubudu Samarakoon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I supervise MSc students at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mn.uio.no/ifi/&#34;&gt;Department of Informatics, University of Oslo&lt;/a&gt;, which have included projects on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duo.uio.no/handle/10852/38306&#34;&gt;text mining of clinical trial data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duo.uio.no/handle/10852/41622&#34;&gt;evaluation of methods for cancer driver gene prediction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duo.uio.no/handle/10852/53017&#34;&gt;cluster analysis of data from genome-wide association studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duo.uio.no/handle/10852/57756&#34;&gt;comparison of somatic and germline mutational spectra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>